Matthew Rumble

Creative Programmer

Matthew Rumble

6526 Cottonwood Cir Dublin, CA 94568

707.710.091 rumble7497@mydusd.org

Skills

I have been coding video games ever since I was twelve years old. I wanted to learn how to make my own games and I have been making 3D and 2D games ever since on my free time as a hobby. I have learned and practiced with many different coding languages such as Java, C#, Python, and HTML.

Experience

Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2017 - Dublin High School, CA

I have always enjoyed coding ever since I was younger when I was teaching myself how to make my own simple platformer games. I have familiarized myself with a variety of languages and programs.

Robotic Engineer / Mechanical and Software Director

JANUARY 2015- JUNE 2017, Fallon Middle School CA

For over three years I have been working with Lego NXT robots and currently own an EV3 robot that I practice coding and building on. Back in middle school our team won the robotics tournament of completing challenges and we got featured on the school's home page of their website.

Filmmaker and Producer / Editor and Filmer

FEBRUARY 2012 - NOVEMBER 2017, DUBLIN, CA

I currently edit and produce my own content and films for my channel on YouTube. I have entered film contests and create animations/videos for school projects. I have been studying and improving my editing and videography work for over 5 years each week, constantly increasing the quality of the videos I create. I strive to make content that when I look back on it, it will be something that I will be proud of years later.

Education

Dublin High School / Freshman

August 2017 - June 2017 Dublin, CA

I work to put in the best effort in all my school assignments. I currently stand strong with straight A's in all my classes continuing from middle school where I constantly made Principal's Honor Roll each year. I believe in trying multiple times to get the result you are happy with. I don't give up the moment something challenging comes my way. I find another way to solve the problem I am stuck with and move forward.

Film and Editing Classes

August 2016 - October 2017 Dublin, CA

For two years in a row over the summer I have been working on making professional films and videos for others to enjoy by also learning the tips and techniques to make my films look even better. I am always open to learning something new especially if it will be beneficial to use in the future of my career or when I create my next videos every week.

Awards

I have won many awards such as winning my 7th grade robotics tournament against other schools and showing up on the front page of the school's website

I won awards for my art and computer drawing skills two years straight against all other school's in the state ending up in the newspaper of the schools around town

I made video games that won awards for their creativity and high graphic design put into the levels I made. Many others have commented that the quality of the graphics and storyline is very impressive several times on each of my games that I have made with different game engines.